Guide to the University of Hartford Studies in Literature ARCH031
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
- Issues, 1969 - 1991
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 12, No. 2, 1980 (Object Bound book vol. 11-12, Box 2)
    Volume 12, Number 2. Imperfect Androgyny and Imperfect Love in the Works of Carson McCullers, By Mary Roberts (pg. 73); The Dark Sources of Love: A Jungian Reading of Two Early James Novels, By Annette Larson Benert (pg. 99); Caddy and Quentin: Anima and Animus Orbited Nice, By Steve Carter (pg. 124); Self and Object Representations in As I Lay Dying, By Deborah Ayer Sitter (pg. 143); The Usable Past: Van Wyck Brooks, By Calvin W. Lane (pg. 156). ERRATUM: Deborah Ayer Sitter, whose article, "Self and Object Representations in As I Lay Dying," appeared in Vol. 12, No. 2, does not teach at Emory University but at Spelman College, also in Atlanta.
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 12, No. 3, 1980 (Object Bound book vol. 11-12, Box 2)
    Volume 12, Number 3. Lyrical Indecencies In "The Twelve Days of Christmas," By Gordon Ross Smith (pg. 164); Islands in the Stream: Death and the Artist, By Richard B. Hovey (pg. 173); Psychological Patterns in the Double Plot of Our Mutual Friend, By Gordon D. Hirsch (pg. 195); Instinct in Tristania, By Sheldon Brivic (pg. 222).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 13, No. 1, 1981 (Object Bound book vol. 13-16, No. 1, Box 2)
    Volume 13, Number 1. John Inglesant, Victorian Cavalier: History as Faith in the 1880s, By Joanne Hutchinson (pg. 1); Contradictions Unresolved: Figural Art in the 1880s, By Susan Casteras (pg. 17); The Artists' Colony at Broadway, England, By Beth Treadway (pg. 41); Eden and Apocalypse: William Morris' Marxist Vision in the 1880s, By Carole Silver (pg. 62); Jude the Obscure: A Psychoanalytic Study, By Carol and Duane Edwards (pg. 78). This issue is dedicated to the memory of ELEANOR BLACKMAN MANHEIM, 1901 - 1981, associated with University of Hartford Studies in Literature as Associate Editor since its founding in 1968. This is a special issue which "collects papers (not delivered at the conference itself) on the art, religion, history, and literature of that decade in which High Victorianism was being challenged by forces that would shape the modern world."
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 13, No. 2, 1981 (Object Bound book vol. 13-16, No. 1, Box 3)
    Volume 13, Number 2. "The Birth-Mark": A Deathmark, By James Quinn and Ross Baldessarini, (pg. 91); Antiquity in The Scarlet Letter: The Primary Sources, By Earl R. Hutchison, Sr.(pg. 99); Pierre's Sexuality: A Psychoanalytic Interpretation of Herman Melville's Pierre, or, the Ambiguities, By Paula Miner-Quinn (pg. 111); "Rappaccini's Daughter" and the Art of Dreaming, By Martin Karlow (pg. 122); Journals Received (pg. 136).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 13, No. 3, 1981 (Object Bound book vol. 13-16, No. 1, Box 3)
    Voume 13, Number 3. Pictorialism and the Poetry of John Milton, By John T. Shawcross (pg.143); The Historian as Dramatist: Realpolitik and Morality in Thucydides' "Melian Debate," By Stephen E. Tabachnik (pg. 165); Brecht's The Rise and Fall of the Ctty of Mahagonny and The Good Woman of Setzuan: Beyond Marxism, By Zsuzsanna Ozsvath (pg. 178); Miltonic Topics, Reviews of Jean H. Hagstrum's Sex and Sensibility: Ideal and Erotic Love From Milton to Mozart and Edward LeComte's A Dictionary of Puns in Milton 's English Poetry, By Robert A. Logan III (pg. 187); Teachable Movies, A review of Alexander Sesonske's Jean Renoir: The French Films, 1924-1939, By Paul H. Stacy (pg. 191); Hemingway at the Movies, A review of Frank M. Laurence's Hemingway and the Movies, By Catherine Barnes Stevenson (pg. 196); Melville in the Pacific, A review of T. Walter Herbert's Marquesan Encounters: Melville and the Meaning of Civilization, By Robert Hillier (pg. 198); Short Reviews (pg. 201); Books Received (pg. 207).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 14, No. 1, 1982 (Object Bound book vol. 13-16, No. 1, Box 3)
    Volume 14, Number 1. Washington Square: James and 'The Deeper Psychology', By Richard B. Hovey (pg. 1); Further Reflections on Plath's "Mirror," By Robert Kloss (pg. 11); Deadly Serious Play: Robert Frost's "Design" By David Kann (pg. 23); Theatre of Clouds: Imaginal Reality and the Idea of the Postmodem, By Michael Sexson (pg. 33); Supplement: Offprint from Literature and Psychology, Volume XXXI, Number 1 (1981), "OUTSIDE LOOKING IN: Evidences of Primal-Scene Fantasy in Hawthorne's Fiction." By Leonard F. Manheim (pg. 41).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 14, No. 2, 1982 (Object Bound book vol. 13-16, No. 1, Box 3)
    Volume 14, Number 2. Mayhew's Book of Lists, By Nancy Aycock Metz (pg. 41); Elizabeth Gaskell and the Question of Liberal Education, By Linda Seidel Costic (pg. 50); Brainwashing and Oliver Twist, By Benjamin Brody (pg. 61); The Oedipal Triangle in Pater's "Hippolytus Veiled," By Natalie Schroeder (pg.67). BOOK REVIEWS: Man's Estate: Masculine Identity in Shakespeare, By Robert A. Logan III, (pg.77); Romanticism and Ideology, By Deborah Gutschera (pg.80); The Underside of Shaw, By Alan Brody (pg. 82).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 14, No. 3, 1982 (Object Bound book vol. 13-16, No. 1, Box 3)
    Volume 14, Number 3. The Child Archetype and Modern Primitivism, Kosinski's The Painted Bird, By John H. Hanson (pg. 85); Fairfax, Churchill, and Jane Austen's Emma, By Ralph Stewart (pg. 96); Rossetti: The Failure of Eros, By Stephen Gurney (pg. 101). BOOK REVIEWS: Women of Learning, By Catherine Barnes Stevenson (pg. 117); Exchanging Gifts, By Paul H. Stacy (pg. 119); O'Neill On Kinship, By Robert M. Como (pg. 123); Literature and Psychology in Germany, By Michael Klaber (pg. 126); Is There a Text in this Book?, By William L. Stull (pg. 128). BOOKSAND JOURNALS RECENED (Edited by Charles L. Ross): Journals Received (pg. 132); Books Received (pg. 135).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 15, No. 1, 1983 (Object Bound book vol. 13-16, No. 1, Box 3)
    Volume 15, Number 1. IN MEMORIAM - LEONARD FALK MANHEIM, 1902 – 1983. Renaissance Variations on a Theme by Keats, By Paul Barolsky (pg. 1); Blake, The Druids, and the Regeneration of Generation, By Lois Ziegelman (pg 13); E. E. Cummings' Sleight-of-Hand: Perceptual Ambiguity in His Early Poetry, Painting, and Career, By Milton A. Cohen (pg. 33); Parataxie Distortion and Group Process in Stephen Crane's "The Blue Hotel," By Charles L. Proudfit (pg. 47).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 15, No. 2, 1983 (Object Bound book vol. 13-16, No. 1, Box 3)
    Volume 15, Number 2. Tennyson's Stupidity, By Gerhard Joseph (pg. 55); Wilfred Owen: World War and Family Romance, By Thorpe Butler (pg. 63); Beyond the Pleasure Principle: Anne Sexton's "The Death Baby," By Diana Hume George (pg. 75). BOOK REVIEWS: Pictures, Poems, and Programs, By William L. Stull (pg. 93); The Delphic Oracle, By George Michael Evica (pg. 97); The Time Falling Bodies Take to Light, By George Michael Evica (pg. 99).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 15, No. 3 - Vol. 16, No. 1, 1984 (Object Bound book vol. 13-16, No. 1, Box 3)
    Volume 15, Number 3 and Volume 16, Number 1. ESSAYS ON RENAISSANCE LITERATURE AND CONTEMPORARY CRITICISM. Sonnets Courtly and Christian, By William L. Stull (pg. 1); Rhetoric and Poetics in the Italian Religious Sonnet, 1500-1650, By Rinaldina Russell (pg. 16); "Plainness and Truth": The Secular and Spiritual Sonnets of Henry Constable, By J. de Oliveira e Silva (pg. 33); The Shadow and the Real: Typology and the Religious Sonnet, By John H. Ottenhoff (pg. 43); Craft and Purpose in Alabaster's Incarnation Sonnets, By George Klawitter (pg. 60); From "Jove" to "Task-Master": The Transformation from Pagan to Christian Deity in Milton's Sonnets 1-7, By Kay Stanton (pg. 67); "Faining Notable Images of Vertue": Sidney's New Arcadia as Legenda Sanctorum, By Margaret P. Hannay (pg. 80); Augustinian Psychology in The Faerie Queene Book II, By Carol V. Kaske (pg. 93); Paradise Regained as Hermeneutic Combat, By Mary Ann Radzinowicz (pg. 99); Self-Persistence in The Temple: George Herbert's "Artillerie," By Sibyl Lutz Severance (pg. 108); "Count It All Joy": The Affirmative Nature of Deconstruction, By G. Douglas Atkins (pg. 120); Milton's "Various Quills": Psychoanalysis and Protestant Poetics, By Christopher Grose (pg. 129).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 16, No. 2-3, 1984 (Object Bound book vol. 16, No. 2 - Vol. 18, Box 3)
    Volume 16, Number 2 and 3. INTERDISCIPLINARY CRITICISM, Essays in Memory of Leonard Manheim. "The essays in this special double issue were commissioned to honor the late Leonard Manheim 1902-1983), founder and editor of Literature and Psychology (1951-1967) and University of Hartford Studies in Literature (1969-1983), teacher, controversialist, and inspiring colleague." Driving in Gainesville, Florida: The Shared and The Individual in literary Response, By Nonnan Holland (pg. 1); The New Discourse of Mass Culture: Magazines in the 1890s, By Richard Ohmann (pg. 16); Interpretive Extremes: The Old Instrument Players and Recent Literary Criticism, By James Winn (pg. 36); From Mannerism to Modernism: The Playful Artifice of Walter Pater, By Paul Barolsky (pg. 47); Philosophy and Poetry: The New Rapprochement, By Carl Rapp (pg. 58); Understanding and Truth in The Two Cultures, By Paul Armstrong (pg. 70); "There Was Meaning in His Look": The Meeting of Pictorial Models in Joyce's "Nausicaa," By Wendy Steiner (pg. 90); Literary Counselors For the Defense: Socrates and Gandhi, By Jean· Pierre Barricelli (pg. 104); Leonard Manheim as a Dickens Critic, By Michael Steig (pg. 111); Contributors (pg. 116).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 17, No. 1, 1985 (Object Bound book vol. 16, No. 2 - Vol. 18, Box 3)
    Volume 17, Number 1. Christina Rossetti's "Goblin Market": A Paradigm for Nineteenth Century Anorexia Nervosa, By Paula Marantz Cohen (pg. 1); E. M. Forster's The Longest Journey: Doubled Offspring and Ambivalent Mothers, By M. D. Faber (pg. 19); Incest and The Good Community in Brecht's Later Plays, By Sammy McLean (pg. 36). BOOK REVIEWS: Shaw's Darker Side, By Alan Brody (pg. 47); The Eternal Question Mark, By Alan Brody (pg. 50); Hardy's Mournful Manysidedness, By Peter J. Casagrande(pg. 52); Heroes and Antiheroes, By Alicia [correct spelling is Alycia] Evica (pg. 55); The Semi-Apocalypse, By Paul H. Stacy (pg. 57); Contributors (pg. 59).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 17, No. 2, 1985 (Object Bound book vol. 16, No. 2 - Vol. 18)
    Voume 17, Number 2. Preface (pg ii); "Taking the Measure of Theoretical Models," By Austin E. Quigley (pg. 1); "Temporality, Knowledge, and the Social Dimensions of Metaphor," By David J. Langston (pg. 13); "Fable and the Epistemology of Expanding Narrative: An Example from the Roman de la Rose," By Kenneth J. Knoespel (pg. 28); "Reading Figures: The Cognitive Powers of Metaphor," By Paul B. Armstrong (pg. 49); Contributors (pg. 68).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 17, No. 3, 1985 (Object Bound book vol. 16, No. 2 - Vol. 18, Box 3)
    Volume 17, Number 3. "To Play in the Socratic Manner": Oxymoron in Milton's At a Vacation Exercise in the Colledge, By Mary Ann Radzinowicz (pg. 1); Henry James, E. D. Hirsch, and Relative Readability: A Note on the Style of The Turn of the Screw, By Brooke K. Horvath (pg.12); Frank Norris's The Pit as Autobiography, By Edwin Haviland Miller (pg. 18); The Fatal Lady in Margaret Atwood's Lady Oracle, By Judith A. Spector (pg. 33); Ressentient Heroes, By Frederick B. Warner, Jr. (pg.45); A Performance of Ambivalence, By Joseph A. Byrnes (pg. 49); Joycean Jouissance and the Artist-God, By Suzette A. Henke (pg. 52); Imagination's Silent Workings, By Laurence Lockridge (pg. 56); Contributors (pg. 59).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 18, No. 1, 1986 (Object Bound book vol. 16, No. 2 - Vol. 18, Box 3)
    Volume 18, Number 1. Guilt and Shame in Early American Children's Literature: A Comparison of John S. C. Abbott's The Child at Home and Jacob Abbott's Rollo Books, By Mark I. West (pg. 1); The 'Hidden Agenda' of Winston Smith: Pathological Narcissism and 1984, By J. Brooks Bouson (pg. 8); Sentimental Idealization as Exploitation: The Dilemma of Aboriginal Portraiture in The Australian Novel, By Patrick Brady (pg. 21); Death is a Woman, Death is a Man: Anne Sexton's Green Girls and The Leaves That Talk, By Diana Hume George (pg. 31).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 18, No. 2-3, 1986 (Object Bound book vol. 16, No. 2 - Vol. 18, Box 3)
    Volume 18, Number 2 and 3. TEXTS OF THE HOLOCAUST, Edited by CHARLES L. ROSS and JAMES E. YOUNG. Preface (pg. iv); 'History' and Variant 'Readings' of the Shoah, By Steven T. Katz (pg. 1); Writing at the Edge: The Holocaust as Text in Israeli Literature, By Sidra DeKoven Ezrahi (pg.14); Yiddish Poetry: From Vilna to Tel Aviv, Lublin to New York, By Anita Norich (pg.27); Reflections on a Video Archive for Holocaust Testimonies, By Geoffrey H. Hartman (pg. 36); Documenting the Witness: On Viewing and Interpreting Holocaust Video Testimony, By James E. Young (pg. 41); Holocaust Literature for Children: The Presentation of Evil, By James F. Farnham (pg. 55); In the Shadow: Three Poems, By Geoffrey H. Hartman (pg. 63); The Troubled Legacy of the Holocaust in Israeli Literature: A Response to Sidra DeKoven Ezrahi, By Eli Pfefferkorn (pg. 66); The Text of Nazis' Extermination Propaganda, By Lothar Kahn (pg. 74); Contributors (pg. 78).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 19, No. 1, 1987 (Object Bound book vol. 19-20, Box 3)
    Volume 19, Number 1. Preface by G. S. Rousseau (pg. ii); "The Discourse(s) of Literature and Science," by G. S. Rousseau (pg. 1); "Literature and Science: The Present State of the Field," By Stuart Peterfreund (pg. 25); "Literature and Science: Towards a New Literary History," By E. S. Shaffer (pg. 37); "Literature and Science: Future Possibilities," By John Neubauer (pg. 53).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 19, No. 2-3, 1987 (Object Bound book vol. 19-20, Box 3)
    Volume 19, Number 2 and 3. The Sexual Attitudes of Marlowe and Shakespeare, by Robert A. Logan (pg. 1); Anthony and Cleopatra: The Birth and Death of Androgny, by James J. Greene (pg. 24); The Pattern of the Myth of Narcissus in Daniel Deronda, by Peggy Ruth Fitzhugh Johnstone (pg. 45); Victorian Discourses on Sexuality and Religion, by John Maynard (pg. 61); Icons and Iconoclasts, by Mary Ann Radzinowicz (pg. 70); Women and Psychiatry in the Nineteenth Century, by Dianne Hunter (pg. 73); The Modernity of Pater, by Paul Barolsky (pg. 76); Men and Their Superiority, by Paul H. Stacy (pg. 79); Contributors (pg. 86).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 20, No. 1, 1988 (Object Bound book vol. 19-20, Box 3)
    Volume 20, Number 1. Foreword, by Robert A. Logan, III (pg. ii); Marlowe, Shakespeare, and The Nature of Biographical Evidence, by Constance Brown Kuriyama (pg. 1); The Dialectic of Gender in Four of Marlowe's Plays, by Sara Munson Deats (pg. 13); Tamburlaine and The Art of Destruction, by Matthew N. Proser (pg. 37); Doctor Faustus: The Textual Problem, by Roma Gill (pg. 52); A Reply to Eli Pfefferkorn, by Sidra DeKoven Ezrahi (pg. 62); Contributors (pg. 63).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 20, No. 2, 1988 (Object Bound book vol. 19-20, Box 3)
    Volume 20, Number 2. "'Repining Restlesnesse': On the Nature of Desire in Blake, Tennyson, and Fairy Tales," by J. Evetts-Secker (pg. 1); "Hardy and the Narcissistic Vision: 'The Shade from His Own Soul Upthrown,'" by Lawrence J. Starzyk (pg. 19); "Trans(re)ference: The Nature of James Strachey's Discipleship," by Perry Meisel (pg. 33); "Beyond Desire: The Conversion of Bob Dylan," by James W. Earl (pg. 46); "Empson on Marlowe," by John T. Shawcross (pg. 64); Contributors (pg. 69).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 20, No. 3, 1988 (Object Bound book vol. 19-20, Box 3)
    Volume 20, Number 3. John Keats and the Pre-Raphaelite Brotherhood: Pictorial Poetry and Narrative Painting, by Wayne Cook (pg. 1); Information and the Imminent Death of Oecipa Maas, by Dean A. Ward (pg. 24); To Conceal and Reveal Truth: The Functions of Dialogue in Montaigne's Essais, by Frieda S. Brown (pg. 38); The Awful English Language, by Thomas Grant (pg. 41); Interpretive Subversions, by Dianne Hunter (pg. 47); Greenblatt's Negotiations: Fictionalizing History and Literature, by Robert A. Logan (pg. 51); Tudor Women: Strong in the Faith, by Mary Ann Radzinowicz (pg. 55); If I Could Tell You, by Gordon Clark Ramsey (pg. 58); Pater's Familias, by Jeffrey L. Spear (pg. 61), Index to Volumes Xl-XX (1979-1988) (pg. 64); Contributors (pg. 77).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 21, No. 1, 1989 (Object Bound book vol. 21-23, Box 3)
    Volume 21, Number 1. ESSAYS: FREDERICK GARBER, Re Positioning The Syntaxes of Barbara Kruger (pg. 3); PATRICK COLM HOGAN, Influxes of Influence: Agonists Hurl Odyssean Mythpuns and Crackquips Aristotelian Designs Thought Likely (pg. 26); DANA A. HELLER, Shifting Gears: Transmission and Flight in Mona Simpson's Anywhere But Here (pg. 37). REVIEWS: MARK A. R. FACKNITZ, The Ethics of Fiction (pg. 45); MATTHEW N. PROSER, Christopher Marlowe and Canterbury (pg. 48); CATHERINE BARNES STEVENSON, The Poetics of Protest (pg. 51); GLADYS CRANE, Feminism and Theatre (pg. 54); GAIL REITENBACH, Heterogeneity in Feminist Texts (pg. 57); NOTES ON CONTRIBUTORS (pg. 60).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 21, No. 2, 1989 (Object Bound book vol. 21-23)
    Volume 21, Number 2. ESSAYS: Bruce Clarke, Circe's Metamorphoses: Late Classical and Early Modem Readings of the Odyssey and Ovid's Metamorphoses (pg. 3); John C. Long, The Scene at the Sickbed in Poe, Hawthorne, and Whitman: The Clinic as Discourse in Tales and Poems of Morbid Physic (pg. 21); James E. Boasberg, Chancery as Megalosaurus: Lawyers, Courts, and Society in Bleak House (pg. 38). REVIEWS: Thomas Pughe, Saving the Document (pg. 61); Gladys Crane, Shakespeare Sounded Soundly (pg. 64); Sidonie Smith, The Private Self: Women's Autobiography (pg. 67); NOTES ON CONTRIBUTORS (pg. 71).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 21, No. 3, 1989 (Object Bound book vol. 21-23, Box 3)
    Volume 21, Number 3. ESSAYS: BARRY KEITH GRANT, "Jungle Nights In Harlem": Jazz, Ideology, and the animated Cartoon (pg. 3); KRIN GABBARD, Wrong Man With A Horn (pg.13); CHRISTOPHER HARLOS, "Swinging London" and the Jazz Soundtrack: Alfie and Blow-Up (pg. 25); STEVEN B. ELWORTH, Ella, Teddy, and the Singing Fence Permutations of the Utopian in Baillie's All My Life (pg. 39). REVIEWS: THOMAS GRANT, Nagging Wags: Women Humorists Strike Back (pg. 47); BRUCE CLARKE, Sacred Truth, Complex Tropes, Critical Misreadings (pg. 55); HARTWIG ISERNHAGEN, History or Biography (pg. 61); NOTES ON CONTRIBUTORS (pg. 64).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 22, No. 1, 1990 (Object Bound book vol. 21-23)
    Volume 22, Number 1. ESSAYS: DAN DOLL, Swift and Brobdingnagian Law (pg. 3); MAUREEN TURIM, Griffith and the Victorian Sea (pg. 17); JACQUELINE COSTELLO, When Worlds Collide: Freedom, Freud, and Jung in John Fowles's Daniel Martin (pg. 31). REVIEW ESSAY: DAVID GLOVER, At the Edges of Discourse: Wilkie Collins, History, and Literary Theory (pg. 45). REVIEWS: DANA POLAN, Doing What Comes Naturally (pg. 53); CATHERINE BARNES STEVENSON, Edging Women Out (pg. 58); NOTES ON CONTRIBUTORS (pg. 63).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 22, No. 2-3, 1990 (Object Bound book vol. 21-23, Box 3)
    Volume 22, Number 2 and 3. ESSAYS: MELINDA BARLOW, The Peculiar Light of Thought: Jean Epstein and the Sublime (pg. 3); RICHARD BOYD, Mimetic Desire and the American Revolution: Hawthorne's "Lady Eleanore's Mantle" (pg. 22); MARGIE BURNS, Easy Rider and Deliverance, or, The Death of the Sixties (pg. 44); EARL G. INGERSOLL, Troping and the Machine in Thomas Hardy's The Mayor of Casterbridge (pg. 59). REVIEW ESSAYS: FREDERICK GARBER, Scenes of Self-Locating (pg. 68); MARK CONROY, To Politicize the Critic (pg. 81); DANA POLAN, The Telephone Book and the Pencil (pg. 91). REVIEWS: ERNEST B. GILMAN, Michelangelo's Self Fashioning (pg. 98); MADONNE MINER, "The More It Changes, The More lt Stays The Same" (pg. 102);JOHN McGOWAN, Gone Fishing (pg. 107); MICHAEL WALSH, Joyce in Paris (pg. 110); NOTES ON CONTRIBUTORS (pg. 115); IN FUTURE ISSUES (pg. 116).
  - University of Hartford Studies in Literature, Vol. 23, No. 1, 1991 (Object Bound book vol. 21-23)
    Volume 23, Number 1. ESSAYS: GARRY M. LEONARD, The Virgin Mary and the Urge in Gerty: The Packaging of Desire in the "Nausicaa" Chapter of Ulysses (pg. 3); ROBERT J. TORRY, Framing the Father: Oedipus and Representation in Bambi (pg. 24); JONATHAN HAVEY, Kleinian Developmental Narrative and What Maisie Knew (pg. 34). REVIEWS: MAUREEN TURIM, Secondary Contradictions in the First Place (pg. 48); ROBERT A. LOGAN, Playing With Boundaries (pg. 53); MARK CONROY, Warpaths: de Man's War, Our Heidegger, and Notre Après-Guerre (pg. 67); DANA POLAN, Reinventing History: Jameson's Postmodernism (pg. 78). NOTES ON CONTRIBUTORS (pg. 85). IN FUTURE ISSUES (pg. 87).